{"componentChunkName":"component---src-templates-establishment-page-js","path":"/establishment/1514","result":{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"1514","name":"Elias Donuts","address":"19231 Grand River Ave.","zipcode":"48223","owner":"Elias Donuts Inc/Hanna Mikhail","licenseNumber":"035734","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":null,"reviewFrequencyDays":"335","coords":"-83.23104,42.40557","geojson":{"id":"1514","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.231043099,42.405573778]},"properties":{"name":"Elias Donuts","owner":"Elias Donuts Inc/Hanna Mikhail","address":"19231 Grand River Ave.","zipcode":"48223","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":null,"license_number":"035734","establishmentid":"1514","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"335","most_recent_license_date":"2023-04-14"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"2754","name":"Cheers/Hopz","address":"19244 Grand River Ave.","zipcode":"48219"},{"establishmentid":"1995","name":"Little Caesar's Pizza #168","address":"19116 Grand River Ave.","zipcode":"48223"},{"establishmentid":"685","name":"George's Ham and Corned Beef","address":"19505 Grand River Ave.","zipcode":"48223"},{"establishmentid":"51623214","name":"Lemonade & Beyond","address":"19361 Bretton","zipcode":"48223"},{"establishmentid":"51623705","name":"Pressed Juice Bar LLC (Juicing with Jai)","address":"19550 Grand River","zipcode":"48223"},{"establishmentid":"2344","name":"Auntie Betty's Cafe","address":"19601 Grand River Ave.","zipcode":"48223"},{"establishmentid":"1369","name":"Blue Moon","address":"19614 Grand River Ave.","zipcode":"48223"},{"establishmentid":"5412","name":"Detroit Vegan Soul","address":"19614 Grand River","zipcode":"48223"},{"establishmentid":"51623959","name":"Cutz Cafe","address":"19655 Grand River Ave.","zipcode":"48223"},{"establishmentid":"904","name":"Cooke Elementary","address":"18800 Puritan ","zipcode":"48219"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"61889","inspectionDate":"2023-03-19T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"7-102.11","violationDescription":"Working containers used for storing POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS such as cleaners and SANITIZERS taken from bulk supplies shall be clearly and individually identified with the common name of the material. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Working containers-toxics","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not labeled as to content","subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2023-03-20T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135Â° F.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Dispensing utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly stored","subProblem":"","location":"FRONT COUNTER/AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2023-03-20T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Missing","subProblem":"","location":"RESTAURANT","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"60320","inspectionDate":"2022-08-29T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"7-201.11","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL shall be stored so they can not contaminate FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES by:   \n(A) Separating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL by spacing or partitioning; (P) and   \n(B) Locating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL in an area that is not above FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.  This paragraph does not apply to EQUIPMENT and UTENSIL cleaners and sanitizers that are stored in WAREWASHING areas for availability and convenience if the materials are stored to prevent contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not separated from","subProblem":"Single-use items","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2022-08-30T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"55912","inspectionDate":"2021-08-08T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"7-201.11","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL shall be stored so they can not contaminate FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES by:   \n(A) Separating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL by spacing or partitioning; (P) and   \n(B) Locating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL in an area that is not above FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.  This paragraph does not apply to EQUIPMENT and UTENSIL cleaners and sanitizers that are stored in WAREWASHING areas for availability and convenience if the materials are stored to prevent contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not separated from","subProblem":"Single-use items","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2021-08-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-101.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be safe, unADULTERATED and honestly presented. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Dishonestly presented","subProblem":"","location":"DRY STORAGE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2021-08-09T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"53929","inspectionDate":"2021-01-14T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Complaint","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"52854","inspectionDate":"2020-09-15T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Complaint","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"52260","inspectionDate":"2020-07-27T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Complaint","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"52065","inspectionDate":"2020-07-21T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"45580","inspectionDate":"2019-03-11T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"7-204.11","violationDescription":"Chemical SANITIZERS and other chemical antimicrobials applied to FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES shall meet the requirements specified in this code. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Sanitizer(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not approved for use","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-03-12T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discontinue use.  Provide approved source."},{"violationCode":"7-202.12","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS shall be:    \n(A) Used according to:      \n(1) LAW and this Code,   \n(2) Manufacturer's use directions included in labeling, and, for a pesticide, manufacturer's label instructions that state that use is allowed in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, (P)   \n(3) The conditions of certification, if certification is required, for use of the pest control materials, (P) and   \n(4) Additional conditions that may be established by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY; and\n(B) Applied so that:      \n(1) A HAZARD to EMPLOYEES or other PERSONS is not constituted, (P) and   \n(2) Contamination including toxic residues due to drip, drain, fog, splash or spray on FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES is prevented, and for a RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE, this is achieved by: (P)      \n(a) Removing the items, (P)   \n(b) Covering the items with impermeable covers, (P) or   \n(c) Taking other appropriate preventive actions, (P) and   \n(d) Cleaning and SANITIZING EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS after the application. (P)  \n(C) A RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE shall be applied only by an applicator certified as defined in 7 USC 136 Definitions, (e) Certified Applicator, of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, or a PERSON under the direct supervision of a certified applicator. (Pf)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not used according to manufacturer's label instructions","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-03-12T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Use according to manufacturer label directions."},{"violationCode":"5-205.11","violationDescription":"(A) A HANDWASHING SINK shall be maintained so that it is accessible at all times for EMPLOYEE use and used for no other purpose. (Pf)\n(B)  An automatic handwashing facility shall be used in accordance with manufacturer's instructions. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Handwashing sink(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not easily accessible","subProblem":"Items stored In","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2019-03-12T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Remove items from handsink.  Do not store items at handsink."},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"floors","problemDescription":"Not clean","subProblem":"","location":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean"},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FRYER AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."}]},{"inspectionid":"41692","inspectionDate":"2018-03-05T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"7-204.11","violationDescription":"Chemical SANITIZERS and other chemical antimicrobials applied to FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES shall meet the requirements specified in this code. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Sanitizer(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not approved for use","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2018-03-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discontinue use.  Provide approved source."},{"violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Raw animal food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/next to","subProblem":"Raw ready-to-eat food(s) Vegetable(s)","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2018-03-06T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store raw animal foods below and away from foods needing little or no further prep."}]},{"inspectionid":"38341","inspectionDate":"2017-03-20T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\n\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2017-03-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above."},{"violationCode":"5-205.11","violationDescription":"(A) A HANDWASHING SINK shall be maintained so that it is accessible at all times for EMPLOYEE use and used for no other purpose. (Pf)\n(B)  An automatic handwashing facility shall be used in accordance with manufacturer's instructions. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Handwashing sink(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not easily accessible","subProblem":"Items stored In","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2017-03-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Remove items from handsink.  Do not store items at handsink."},{"violationCode":"6-302.11","violationDescription":"A supply of toilet tissue shall be available at each toilet.(Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Toilet paper","subItem":"at toilet in restroom","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"RESTROOM(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2017-03-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"violationCode":"3-305.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination by storing the FOOD:\n(1)     In a clean, dry location;\n(2)     Where it is not exposed to splash, dust, or other contamination; and\n(3)     At least 15 cm (6 inches) above the floor, unless otherwise approved.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food item(s) in storage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on floor or less than 6 inches above floor","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store at least 6 inches above the floor."},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null}]}]}],"maxInspectionDate":[{"inspectionDate":"2023-04-25T00:00:00"}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"1514"}},"staticQueryHashes":["3649515864","63159454"]}